RESUME

Vishnu C. purplexedv@gmail.com. +91-7406544045

CAREER SUMMARY:

A senior engineer skilled in DevOps, infrastructure as code, distributed systems on cloud with over 7 years of industry experience. Iam **currently on a sabbatical** and is self employed. Looking for remote and/or full time opportunities.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- --Public Cloud: Amazon Web Services, Google Kubernetes Engine.
- --Linux Systems Administration (RHEL, Ubuntu) & understanding of Linux Internals.
- --Coding experience in Python, Java, Shell Scripting (Bash, AWK) etc.
- --Good understanding of TCP/IP, protocols including past experience on Cisco devices.
- --DevOps tools: Ansible, Terraform, Packer, Jenkins, Docker, Cobbler & Git version control.
- --Other Familiar technologies: MySQL, Kafka, Elasticsearch, Sensu, NewRelic, Bind DNS, DHCPD, IPtables, Apache, Nginx, HAProxy, OpenLDAP, KVM etc.

WORK EXPERIENCE & PROJECTS:

VMWare India

Member of Technical Staff - (June 2017 - March 2018)

- -Development of SLM, a framework written in python and terraform for deploying NSX on cloud.
- -Worked extensively on cloud engineering for availability of NSX cloud on cloud.
- -Build & managed k8s clusters on GCP for container orchestration.

Publicis Razorfish

Senior Cloud Engineer (DevOps) - (March 2015 - Feb 2017)

- -DHL Germany Cloud Migration Delivered DevOps activities & helped move specific workloads to AWS.
- -Application Deployment Framework Developed a Prototype Deployment framework using Python & Ansible.
- -Worked on AWS Shield for Web Application security for Philips e-commerce India.

Cisco Systems

Network Consulting Engineer - (Nov 2014 – March 2015)

- -Support Cisco Sourcefire IPS by working for the Cisco TAC.
- -Worked on signature development for network anomaly & vulnerability detection complemented by snort, nmap etc.

Application Support Engineer - (August 2012 - Sep 2013)

- -Cisco Smartnet Total Care Worked on Cisco's CSPC software that runs a collection software to collect inventory details from Cisco devices.
- -PSS API Supported Cisco API services that interacts with Cisco's Smart net portal.
- -Worked on Systems Hardening to make sure the collectors are free of security vulnerabilities.
- -Performed Automation to convert transport files from customer networks to a format compatible with the smartnet portal using perl scripts.

Candor Solutions

Linux Engineer - (March 2010 - June 2012)

- -Performed Linux systems engineering and fleet of other infrastructure automation activities as a linux engineer.
- -PXELinux based OS deployment: Have successfully configured and maintained a OS deployment server using syslinux which is a suite of lightweight IBM PC MBR bootloaders for starting up computers with the Linux kernel.
- -Implemented OpenDNS with squid as a transparent proxy and iptables to filter internet traffic.
- -Implemented a local mail relay server with webmail to reduce bandwidth consumption by fetching all employee mails to local MTA using fetchmail, dovecot, postfix and squirrelmail.

REMOTE WORK:

DevOps Engineer – Bluemeric – Help develop 'Gopaddle' a kubernetes based cloud Workload Migration tool. (May 2014 - Nov 2014).

OTHER FREELANCE WORK:

- -Technical Trainer Edureka Technical trainer delivering training online.
- -Implementation Engineer Rendered Text Implementation Engineer for Semaphore, a SaaS based CI/CD tool.

IT CERTIFICATIONS:

RHCE(EL-5, EL-6), RHCVA, AWS – SysOps Associate (Expired)

FORMAL EDUCATION:

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics, Amrita Vishwa Vidhyapeetham, 2009.

OTHER INTERESTS & ACTIVITIES:

- Adventure motorcycling on my Royal Enfield.
- Deep interest in Indian classical Music.
- Wildlife photography (I am terrible at this).
- Volunteered for Child Relief & you by joining PAG in Bangalore, India.
